Hello, programmer welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic. So to this topic is their skill for the structured query language
It's a powerful tool for managing and many polluting database and understanding its syntax is the key to become
Proficient in the database management. Okay, so now let's start with the basics. Okay, so first of all here
I can keep in this topic the syntax of the SQL. Okay, so first of all here
I can only define for the new database for here in the SQL and in this inside
First I can create the first syntax for this. Well, this create table, okay
So now just create the table and use the create table statement followed by the table name and their list of column
Along with here the data types, okay
So first of all here, I can start the event create
table and then the table name sample just use the
Employees and here create the parentheses and in this inside
Inside for the column documents. So first of all, I can just type the employee ID
So define here
This is the
employee ID and
It's the integer and
Put the primary key we are I may or I this is a primary key, okay?
And now just bring to the next step. So here I can just start with the first name. Okay, so the first name is the
Barcode and inside the first name suppose like 50. Okay
And next step here insert the last name and
Define here both the
Barcode and create the size of 50, okay?
Next step here use the another statement for each column is integer type and the next here defined for the department
So perfectly just type the department for the
Barcode and inside for the size of 50, okay? So now just
Completely create the table
Just name like the employees with the
Column for example the ID the first name and the last name event department and
Indimplo ID column set the primary key in shooting the values
These in there. Okay, so here I can just understand so now I can just select and
Then execute now you can see here
This comma is completely successful, okay?
And next step here. I can create another
Open another queue and now here insert into so now just inserting data into using for the insert into statement
So first type this the insert
Into and here
Type for here the table name is the employees and in this insight insert first the employee
So this is the employee ID
then
your first name and
The next step here the last name
Then here I can define for the age and also
The department, okay?
So now here perfectly define for the employee ID
Then the first name last name and the department, okay?
So now just next step here I can go in to describe the values and in this insight first of all
I can create for the employee is one and inside for the
suppose like the Johan and
Also here I can create for the last name and the next step here. I can create the ages
Defend for ages 30 and also here to clear for the department of ID, okay?
So now here completely insert for the in the new record the price table with the values for the each column is specified
Okay, so now here I'm going to select an execute and you can see here the one row is affected, okay?
So the two syntax is perfectly done and the next step here
I can create for another syntax now use the selected statement, okay?
So another new query and first of all here
establish select and
Next step and then here I can call them boys. So the em
PL/Y so this one
The employees and here in this selecting for the or column the employee's table denoted by the
Access query return all the code is stored in the employee's table, okay? So now just select and
So now here
click on the select and
You can see here. This is the select information for the employee ID
First name last name and the department, okay next step here. I can click for the most important for another
Syntax for the updated statement, okay?
So now here just keep it in first of all here. I can just type the update the
Employees and now here just create use the same statement declare for days is equal to
35, okay, and also here define for the wire is the word then type for the
Even
employee ID
Is equal to one, okay? So now here select the subtracting the h column for the employee so the ID
35 and
Post is specified for which put the date based on the certain condition, okay? So here now just select and
Just is the queue and you can see here this the one is perfectly affected, okay?
So now just verify this the statement and just go again and
Execute you can see here perfectly update for the age, okay? So previously there was certain update for the I just started, okay?
So here this is completely
update session so
Brief overview of the code syntax in the more practical example
So I hope you find the studio helpful. So stay tuned for more SQL tips and picks
So thank you for watching and happy coding